<?xml version="1.0"?>
<liturgia> <ligne id="0">
<la>Ego D&#xF3;minus Deus tuus appreh&#xE9;ndens manum tuam dic&#xE9;nsque tibi: &#x201C;Ne t&#xED;meas; ego auxili&#xE1;bor tibi. Noli tim&#xE9;re, vermis I&#xE1;cob, h&#xF3;mines ex Israel. Ego auxili&#xE1;bor tibi&#x201D;, dicit D&#xF3;minus et red&#xE9;mptor tuus, Sanctus Israel. Ecce p&#xF3;sui te quasi plaustrum trit&#xFA;rans novum, habens rostra serr&#xE1;ntia. Tritur&#xE1;bis montes et comm&#xED;nues et colles quasi p&#xFA;lverem pones. Ventil&#xE1;bis eos, et ventus tollet eos, et turbo disp&#xE9;rget eos; et tu exsult&#xE1;bis in D&#xF3;mino, in Sancto Israel laet&#xE1;beris. Eg&#xE9;ni et p&#xE1;uperes quaerunt aquas, et non sunt, lingua e&#xF3;rum siti &#xE1;ruit. Ego, D&#xF3;minus, ex&#xE1;udiam eos, Deus Israel non derel&#xED;nquam eos. Ap&#xE9;riam in decalv&#xE1;tis c&#xF3;llibus fl&#xFA;mina et in m&#xE9;dio v&#xE1;llium fontes; ponam des&#xE9;rtum in stagna aqu&#xE1;rum et terram &#xE1;ridam in rivos aqu&#xE1;rum. Plant&#xE1;bo in des&#xE9;rto cedrum, ac&#xE1;ciam et myrtum et lignum ol&#xED;vae; ponam in solit&#xFA;dine ab&#xED;etem, ulmum et cupr&#xE9;ssum simul, ut v&#xED;deant et sciant et rec&#xF3;gitent et int&#xE9;llegant p&#xE1;riter quia manus D&#xF3;mini fecit hoc, et Sanctus Israel cre&#xE1;vit illud.</la><en>For I, the LORD your God, hold your right hand; it is I who say to you, "Fear not, I will help you." Fear not, you worm Jacob, you men of Israel! I will help you, says the LORD; your Redeemer is the Holy One of Israel. Behold, I will make of you a threshing sledge, new, sharp, and having teeth; you shall thresh the mountains and crush them, and you shall make the hills like chaff; You shall winnow them and the wind shall carry them away, and the tempest shall scatter them. And you shall rejoice in the LORD; in the Holy One of Israel you shall glory. When the poor and needy seek water, and there is none, and their tongue is parched with thirst, I the LORD will answer them, I the God of Israel will not forsake them. I will open rivers on the bare heights, and fountains in the midst of the valleys; I will make the wilderness a pool of water, and the dry land springs of water. I will put in the wilderness the cedar, the acacia, the myrtle, and the olive; I will set in the desert the cypress, the plane and the pine together; that men may see and know, may consider and understand together, that the hand of the LORD has done this, the Holy One of Israel has created it.</en></ligne>
<ligne id="1">
</ligne>
<ligne id="2">
</ligne>
<ligne id="3">
<la>ted it."</la></ligne>
<ligne id="4">
</ligne>
</liturgia>
